expertrating.com 2017-06-06

# ExpertRating - Online Certification and Employment Testing

* Last Updated: December 22nd, 2016 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [ https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request ](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

ExpertRating Solutions is committed to protecting your privacy. We have established this privacy policy to communicate our information practices through this statement, pertaining to the collection, use and protection of the personal information we collect. This privacy policy applies exclusively to the Website [ www.expertrating.com](http://www.expertrating.com/) . By using this Website, you are providing your consent to the privacy practices disclosed within this statement. 

* What type of user related information do we collect?

ExpertRating collects personal information from users of the Website at different points of registration. Whether registering as affiliate partner, for an employer account or as an individual user, we collect personal information to facilitate your requested service. This collected personal information includes name, email and physical address, phone number, and PayPal I.D. where applicable. Where users’ register for a ‘Live Proctored’ exam, we may also collect during the proctored session information such as a web cam photo I.D., a list of applications running on your system and geographical location are collected as well to maintain the integrity of the proctored session. When a user elects to tell a friend about our Website and service, or in emailing test results, we require third party personal information including name and email to send this one time email. This third party personal information is not used for any secondary or unsolicited purposes, nor is it stored within our database. 

Your friend or owner of the third party information may contact us at [ExpertRating Help Desk ](http://www.expertrating.com/support/issue-submit.asp) to request that we remove this information from our database.   
We also collect sensitive data through a third party payment processor including credit card number and expiration date when processing payments for services purchased from ExpertRating. These third party agents do not share your sensitive information with any third parties and have no authorization to use your personal information for any unsolicited purposes.    
Information collection during re-certification on ExpertRating - When you apply for re-certification, the website collects information related to your previous and current employment. You will be asked for your previous employer's address and current employer's address. This information is solely used for determining whether you are eligible for re-certification without re-taking the test. 

* How does ExpertRating use my information? 

ExpertRating does not send registered users’ of the Website any unsolicited messages. We use your collected information to register accounts, provide access to the services requested, process payments and provide customer service. ExpertRating reserves the right to send users’ notification, administrative and service emails which are a part of the service. Consequently, you cannot opt-out of these communications. 

* Our commitment to data security 

Your personal information is kept strictly confidential through a security system which only allows access to critical information to the company's security team members. This team consists of experienced engineers and staff who are under stringent confidentiality requirements. The security system is backed by the latest technology and ensures that your personal information is fully protected. Your ExpertRating profile which is available to you in your login area is protected through a password. You are advised to keep this password confidential and to ensure that you close the browser window after logging out from ExpertRating, especially if you are using a shared computer. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, while we do our utmost to protect your personal information, ExpertRating cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best efforts to ensure the security of your information on our systems. 

* Our commitment to payment information (credit card number) security 

ExpertRating services can be purchased online through a secure credit card transaction using any major credit card or PayPal. The ecommerce functionality on the site has been provided by [PayPal](http://www.paypal.com/) which is a trusted name in online transaction processing. When you supply your credit card information it is not retained on file by us. Moreover, the transaction takes place on the PayPal secure server which is 100% safe and encrypts the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). When you buy any of our services, it is treated as a sale and your credit card will not be charged again in the future as is the case in subscription sales. [PayPal](http://www.paypal.com/) transactions take place on the PayPal server which is a trusted name in online transaction processing. 

* How you can access or correct your personal information 

ExpertRating Solutions will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You can access and change the personal information that we collect and maintain by logging in at your user account with the username and passwords assigned to your account. You can delete your account and personal information by sending us a request through email or phone. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at ExpertRating [Help Desk](http://www.expertrating.com/support/index.asp). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. 

The login page is at: <http://www.expertrating.com/login.asp>

The users Name cannot be directly changed by you from within the login so as to prevent unauthorized use of our testing services. You must request us for a change of Name by clicking on the "request name change" link within your login area.   
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [ ExpertRating HelpDesk . ](http://www.expertrating.com/support/index.asp)

* Automatically Collected Information

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by ExpertRating. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We use cookies to recognize the user preferences upon return visits. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.   
As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.   
We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as Flash or HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click [here ](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).     
We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here ](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads. 

* Information Sharing and Disclosure 

In certain situations, ExpertRating Solutions may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.   
ExpertRating may be required by law to disclose information to law enforcement, or other government agencies under certain circumstances such as where a formal request has been made in a civil suit, court order, bankruptcy proceedings or subpoena served on the Website. We reserve the right to disclose information in our sole and absolute discretion, where deemed necessary to protecting the safety of our staff, users, the general public, or in protecting our intellectual property. 

* Data Retention 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [ExpertRating Help Desk](http://www.expertrating.com/support/index.asp). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

* Links to 3rd Party Sites 

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Expert Rating Solutions. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit. 

* Social Media Features 

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

* What is our policy if there is a change in our Privacy practices? 

ExpertRating strives to improve the company's privacy policy from time to time. In the event of a material change, emails will automatically be sent out to all users describing the changes in the privacy policy and how they can opt out from the effects of the new privacy policy. Users will clearly be given an opportunity to prohibit any use of information that was not described at the time the initial user information was collected. Moreover, the link to the updated privacy policy will be clearly noted on the home page of the site. 

* What is ExpertRating's policy if the site is sold or merged with another company? 

ExpertRating will do its utmost to ensure that the successor adheres to the same privacy policy. However the privacy practices of the successor company cannot be ascertained before the eventuality of such a takeover occurs. ExpertRating will do its best to inform all registered users about the changes in the privacy practices as soon as the information about the new policy is made available by posting a notice on the Website, or by sending users’ an email to this end. 

* Who should I contact if I have a Privacy related concern? 

If you have any doubts or require clarifications related to the privacy of your information with us, please use our [ contact form ](http://www.expertrating.com/contact.asp) to get in touch with us. 

* Contact Us 

Company Name ExpertRating Solutions  
Physical address Block D, Ground Floor, DLF IT Park, Chandigarh, India  
Phone Number and email address +91-172-4656989, contact(at)expertrating.com
